Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're at a wedding ceremony.
今天我们在一场婚礼上。
Alright, nice!
好的，真不错！
Another nice wedding.
又一场美好的婚礼。
Yeah.
是啊。
But of course, it wouldn't be EnglishPod unless we have something unexpected happening at
但当然，如果没有意外发生，那就不是EnglishPod了，
this wedding.
这场婚礼上。
Okay, so we're going to be talking about hands.
好的，所以我们要聊聊手。
But Marco, what is there to say about a hand?
但是Marco，手有什么好说的呢？
Well, as you may or may not know, each finger has a name on your hand.
嗯，你可能知道也可能不知道，你手上的每根手指都有名字。
Okay.
好的。
So we're going to learn what those names are in English.
所以我们要学习这些名字用英语怎么说。
Perfect.
完美。
And also, we're going to learn about some common phrases that you might hear in an English
而且，我们还要学习一些在英语婚礼上可能听到的常见短语。
wedding.
婚礼上。
Exactly.
没错。
Because I think, exactly because usually it's old English.
因为我觉得，正是因为通常那是古英语。
Maybe English that's not used anymore.
可能是现在不再使用的英语。
Alright.
好的。
Well, I'm excited to find out what this unexpected event is.
嗯，我很想知道这个意外事件是什么。
So let's listen to our dialogue for the first time.
那我们第一次来听对话吧。
The rings, please.
请拿戒指。
May this ring be blessed so he who gives it and she who wears it may abide in peace and
愿这枚戒指被祝福，愿赠予者和佩戴者都能在和平中安居，
continue in love until life's end.
并继续相爱，直到生命尽头。
For this ring I be wed, wear it as a symbol of our love and commitment.
以此戒指，我与你成婚，佩戴它作为我们爱与承诺的象征。
Honey, that's my pinky.
亲爱的，那是我的小指。
That ring goes on the ring finger.
那枚戒指应该戴在无名指上。
This one?
这根吗？
That's my index finger.
那是我的食指。
Oh, right.
哦，对。
This one, right?
这根，对吧？
That's the thumb make.
那是大拇指。
Okay, I got it.
好的，我明白了。
This is the ring finger.
这是无名指。
That's my middle finger, Nick.
那是我的中指，Nick。
This is my ring finger.
这是我的无名指。
Alright, embarrassing moments for the groom.
好吧，新郎的尴尬时刻。
Yes.
是的。
Confusing the fingers in front of all his friends and family.
在所有亲友面前搞混了手指。
Not good.
不太好。
We mentioned before that we're going to learn the names of each finger in your hand, so
我们之前提到过要学习每根手指的名字，所以
let's get started.
我们开始吧。
Let's take a look at these in Language Takeaway.
我们来看看语言要点部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Alright, well, why don't we start with the smallest finger on your hand?
好的，我们为什么不从手上最小的手指开始呢？
The smallest finger on your hand.
手上最小的手指。
That's called the pinky.
那叫小指。
Sometimes people call it the little finger, right?
有时人们也叫它little finger，对吧？
So the pinky.
所以是小指。
And the next finger is the one the groom couldn't find.
下一根手指是新郎找不到的那根。
Okay, the ring finger.
好的，无名指。
The ring finger.
无名指。
So this is, of course, like the name says, where the wedding ring is usually placed.
所以这当然，就像名字说的，是通常戴结婚戒指的地方。
Exactly.
没错。
On this finger.
在这根手指上。
Now, the next one is a controversial finger.
现在，下一根是有争议的手指。
That must be the middle finger.
那一定是中指。
Okay, easy.
好的，简单。
Middle finger.
中指。
So why is it controversial?
那为什么它有争议呢？
Well, you know, if you put your middle finger up and you put all...
嗯，你知道，如果你竖起中指，然后把其他...
Like you're doing right now to me.
就像你现在对我做的那样。
I'm sorry, Marco.
对不起，Marco。
I'll do it this way.
我这样来。
And all other fingers down, you are making a very rude gesture, a rude sign.
其他手指都放下，你就在做一个非常粗鲁的手势，一个粗鲁的标志。
So what would you call that?
那你会怎么称呼它？
I would call that giving the middle finger.
我会叫它竖中指。
Giving the middle finger.
竖中指。
Or, I've also heard the phrase, flip someone off.
或者，我也听过“flip someone off”这个短语。
Yes, or also flip the bird.
是的，或者“flip the bird”。
Flip the bird, exactly.
“Flip the bird”，没错。
Or give him the bird.
或者“give him the bird”。
Yes.
是的。
So these are all phrases that you can use when you are showing only your middle finger
所以这些都是当你只向某人展示中指时
to somebody.
可以用的短语。
It's not very polite.
这不太礼貌。
No, don't do it.
不，别这么做。
Don't do it.
别这么做。
Unless somebody deserves it, I guess.
除非有人活该，我想。
We won't talk about that.
我们就不谈那个了。
But what we will talk about is the next finger.
但我们要谈的是下一根手指。
The index finger.
食指。
Index finger.
So this is the finger you use to point.
这是你用来指东西的手指。
Right.
对。
Yeah.
是的。
The index finger.
食指。
Any idea why they call it the index finger?
知道为什么叫食指吗？
Because when you're looking through the index of a book, you always use this finger.
因为当你翻阅书的索引时，你总是用这根手指。
Right.
对。
I think you also use this finger to pass pages on a book, right?
我想你也用这根手指翻书页，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
Don't believe anything I just told you.
别相信我刚才说的任何话。
Well, we're not sure.
嗯，我们不确定。
Maybe you guys know the real answer to this.
也许你们知道真正的答案。
All right.
好的。
And our last finger, the most important one.
还有我们最后一根手指，最重要的一根。
The thumb.
大拇指。
Thumb.
T-H-U-M-B.
T-H-U-M-B。
The thumb.
大拇指。
Thumb.
Okay.
好的。
So that's the short but fat finger.
那是又短又粗的手指。
The very movable one.
非常灵活的那根。
The movable one.
灵活的那根。
The one that you use to play PlayStation.
你用来玩PlayStation的那根。
Video games.
电子游戏。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So the pronunciation here, do you say the B at the end of this word?
那发音上，这个单词末尾的B要发音吗？
No.
不。
I actually only pronounce the M. The thumb.
我实际上只发M的音。大拇指。
The thumb.
大拇指。
Yeah.
是的。
You wouldn't say the thumb.
你不会说“the thumb”带B音。
No.
不。
Okay.
好的。
So now that we're clear on all five fingers, let's listen to our dialogue again and then
所以现在我们清楚了五根手指，让我们再听一遍对话，然后
we'll come back and talk about these difficult phrases that the priest used.
回来谈谈牧师用的那些难懂的短语。
The rings, please.
请拿戒指。
May this ring be blessed so he who gives it and she who wears it may abide in peace and
愿这枚戒指被祝福，愿赠予者和佩戴者都能在和平中安居，
continue in love until life's end.
并继续相爱，直到生命尽头。
With this ring I, thee wed, wear it as a symbol of our love and commitment.
以此戒指，我与你成婚，佩戴它作为我们爱与承诺的象征。
Honey, that's my pinky.
亲爱的，那是我的小指。
The ring goes on the ring finger.
戒指应该戴在无名指上。
This one?
这根吗？
That's my index finger.
那是我的食指。
Oh, right.
哦，对。
This one, right?
这根，对吧？
That's the thumb, Nick.
那是大拇指，Nick。
Okay.
好的。
I got it.
我明白了。
This is the ring finger.
这是无名指。
That's my middle finger, Nick.
那是我的中指，Nick。
This is my ring finger.
这是我的无名指。
Well, this is really common wedding speak, isn't it?
嗯，这真是常见的婚礼用语，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
It's really common.
真的很常见。
That's what usually the priest or the person who is marrying somebody would say.
这通常是牧师或主持婚礼的人会说的话。
Well, why don't we look at some of these phrases now because it's really interesting to talk
嗯，我们为什么不现在看看这些短语呢，因为谈论它们的含义
about their meaning.
真的很有趣。
So the first one, may this ring be blessed.
所以第一个，“may this ring be blessed”。
May this ring be blessed.
“May this ring be blessed”。
So what does it mean when you bless something or someone?
那么祝福某物或某人是什么意思呢？
Well, usually the religious leader does this, right?
嗯，通常宗教领袖会这样做，对吧？
And he's giving good wishes to that thing.
他是在给那个东西送上美好的祝愿。
Could be for an object or to a person, right?
可以是对物品或对人，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
Yeah.
And so these good wishes usually come from God.
而这些美好的祝愿通常来自上帝。
Okay.
好的。
Great.
太好了。
So what about our next phrase?
那我们的下一个短语呢？
Abide in peace.
“Abide in peace”。
Wow.
哇。
So this verb, abide.
所以这个动词“abide”。
It means to live.
意思是居住。
To live.
居住。
Yeah.
是的。
To be.
存在。
To be in peace.
处于和平中。
Yeah.
是的。
But it's very fancy and I don't know if you use it anymore.
但这很文雅，我不知道现在是否还用。
No.
不。
I mean, you would never use this word in conversation or even very rarely in writing.
我的意思是，你在对话中永远不会用这个词，甚至在写作中也很少用。
It's quite old.
它相当古老。
Yes.
是的。
Definitely.
绝对。
I would agree.
我同意。
So abide in peace.
所以“abide in peace”。
Okay.
好的。
What about our next phrase?
那我们的下一个短语呢？
I like this and it's the common phrase you'll hear in all movies and in all marriages.
我喜欢这个，这是你在所有电影和所有婚礼中都会听到的常见短语。
Yeah.
是的。
With this ring, I thee wed.
“With this ring, I thee wed”。
Okay.
好的。
We've got two words in here that are also older English words.
这里面有两个词也是更古老的英语词汇。
So thee.
所以“thee”。
Thee.
“Thee”。
T-H-E-E.
T-H-E-E。
Thee.
“Thee”。
So this is a middle English term for you.
这是中古英语中“你”的说法。
You.
你。
Yes.
是的。
Right?
对吧？
So can I say, I love thee?
所以我能说“I love thee”吗？
You could.
你可以。
That would be very romantic.
那会非常浪漫。
But also inappropriate for the office.
但在办公室就不合适了。
But it's very old English.
但这是非常古老的英语。
I guess if you're reading Shakespeare, you would definitely come upon this, right?
我想如果你在读莎士比亚，你肯定会遇到这个词，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
And what about wed?
那“wed”呢？
This is also an old word for, an old verb for the action of marrying someone.
这也是一个古老的词，一个古老的动词，表示结婚这个行为。
So I can say, we will be wed next year.
所以我可以这样说：我们明年将结婚。
But don't say that now because you'll sound quite silly.
但现在别这么说，因为听起来会很傻。
Yeah.
嗯。
It's too old-fashioned.
太老套了。
Yeah, I guess so.
嗯，我想也是。
But it's good to know, especially if you guys are reading something a little bit more classical.
但知道这些有好处，尤其是如果你们在读一些更经典的作品。
Or you plan to get married to an English person.
或者你打算和一个英国人结婚。
All right.
好的。
And our last phrase.
还有我们最后一个短语。
Wear it as a symbol of our love and commitment.
戴上它，作为我们爱与承诺的象征。
So now he's referring to the rings, right?
所以他现在指的是戒指，对吧？
Wear the ring as a symbol.
戴上戒指作为象征。
A sign.
一个标志。
A representation.
一种代表。
Yes.
是的。
Of love and commitment.
爱与承诺的象征。
So why would you wear a ring as a symbol of something?
那你为什么要戴戒指作为某物的象征呢？
Well obviously, you know, love, you can't see it, you can't touch it.
很明显，你知道，爱是看不见、摸不着的。
Right.
对。
So you need something to show you that it's there.
所以你需要一些东西来向你表明它存在。
So you need a sign of that love.
所以你需要一个爱的标志。
Something that you can see.
一些你能看到的东西。
So that's what the ring represents.
这就是戒指所代表的。
Yeah.
嗯。
But how about this word, commitment?
那“commitment”这个词呢？
A commitment is a strong promise.
承诺是一个强有力的誓言。
So you promise to love that person, to take care of them, etc.
所以你承诺爱那个人，照顾他们等等。
Yeah.
嗯。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
So now we are a little bit more familiar with some of the language you hear in a wedding
所以现在我们对婚礼上听到的一些用语更熟悉了
ceremony.
仪式。
And we also know all of the names of the fingers.
而且我们也知道了所有手指的名称。
Exactly.
没错。
So why don't we listen to the dialogue one more time to hear these all in context.
那我们为什么不把对话再听一遍，在上下文中听听这些词呢？
The rings please.
请把戒指拿来。
May this ring be blessed so he who gives it and she who wears it may abide in peace and
愿这枚戒指被祝福，这样给予它的人和佩戴它的人都能在和平中安住，
continue in love until life's end.
并继续相爱，直到生命尽头。
And may this ring I be wed wear it as a symbol of our love and commitment.
愿我结婚时佩戴这枚戒指，作为我们爱与承诺的象征。
Honey, that's my pinky.
亲爱的，那是我的小指。
That ring goes on the ring finger.
那枚戒指应该戴在无名指上。
This one?
这根吗？
That's my index finger.
那是我的食指。
Oh, right.
哦，对。
This one, right?
这根，对吧？
That's the thumb make.
那是大拇指。
Okay, I got it.
好了，我明白了。
This is the ring finger.
这是无名指。
That's my middle finger, Nick.
那是我的中指，尼克。
This is my ring finger.
这是我的无名指。
All right, so now it's perfectly clear and a romantic dialogue in the end.
好了，现在完全清楚了，最后还有一段浪漫的对话。
Yeah, very romantic.
嗯，非常浪漫。
Although a little bit embarrassing.
虽然有点尴尬。
Yeah.
嗯。
So what about wedding rings?
那结婚戒指呢？
Now we have different types of rings, right?
现在我们有不同类型的戒指，对吧？
We have the wedding ring, the one that we just heard, but we also have an engagement
我们有结婚戒指，就是我们刚才听到的那种，但我们还有订婚
ring.
戒指。
Yes, yeah.
是的，没错。
In most English speaking countries, the woman is very, very lucky because she gets two rings.
在大多数英语国家，女人非常非常幸运，因为她能得到两枚戒指。
So when the man asks her to marry him, he gives her a diamond.
所以当男人向她求婚时，他会给她一颗钻石。
A diamond ring.
一枚钻石戒指。
That is usually, that's the engagement ring.
那通常是订婚戒指。
And it's really, really important that he does this.
他这样做真的非常重要。
And it's also really important that he spends a lot of money on the diamond.
而且他在钻石上花很多钱也非常重要。
Yeah, I know about this.
嗯，我知道这个。
Weddings are forever, right?
婚礼是永恒的，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
And the tradition is you must spend at least one month's salary.
传统是你必须花至少一个月的工资。
Wow.
哇。
Is that it?
就这样吗？
Yeah.
嗯。
So the girl gets a diamond engagement ring, and then on wedding day, she gets the wedding
所以女孩得到一枚钻石订婚戒指，然后在婚礼当天，她得到结婚
ring.
戒指。
Yes.
是的。
And usually, will she wear both of them?
通常，她会两枚都戴吗？
Yeah, she'll always wear both of them.
嗯，她会一直两枚都戴。
So the engagement ring goes closest to you, and then the wedding ring on top.
所以订婚戒指戴在最靠近你的位置，然后结婚戒指戴在上面。
And the engagement ring, it represents?
订婚戒指代表什么？
The commitment to marry her.
娶她的承诺。
No, wait, the commitment from the man to marry her.
不，等等，是男人娶她的承诺。
Okay, so it's a symbol that they will get married.
好的，所以这是一个他们会结婚的象征。
Yes, it's a symbol of the promise.
是的，这是承诺的象征。
Now what happens if they break up and they don't get married?
那如果他们分手了，不结婚了怎么办？
Does he get the ring back?
他能拿回戒指吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Okay, here's the rule.
好的，规则是这样的。
If he was a jerk, no.
如果他是混蛋，就不行。
But if it was sort of like a happy breakup, then okay.
但如果算是和平分手，那就可以。
Okay.
好的。
I guess it's a big risk, right?
我想这是个很大的风险，对吧？
Yeah.
嗯。
All right.
好的。
That's it for today, guys.
今天就到这里吧，各位。
Let us know if you guys have any interesting wedding stories.
如果你们有任何有趣的婚礼故事，请告诉我们。
I know that sometimes weddings can be embarrassing, people, I don't know, objecting, maybe I've
我知道有时候婚礼会很尴尬，比如有人反对，或者我见过新郎晕倒。
seen the groom faint.
甚至掉进游泳池。
Or even fall in a pool.
掉进游泳池。
Fall in a pool.
So if you have any stories, please share them with us.
所以如果你们有故事，请和我们分享。
Come to EnglishPod.com.
来EnglishPod.com。
And also if you have any questions or doubts, Erica and I are always there to answer them.
另外，如果你们有任何问题或疑问，我和Erica随时都在那里回答。
Well thanks for listening to this lesson, everyone.
好了，感谢大家收听这节课。
And until next time, goodbye.
下次再见，拜拜。